Guide to the Linda May Papers 2015-009
University of Houston Libraries Special Collections
Linda May Papers
1969-2006
1970-2000
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
May, Linda
2015-009
6.0 Linear Feet
This collection contains the papers of Linda May, a Houston feminist activist who coordinated numerous national and global women's conferences and represented the American Jewish Coalition at the 1985 and 1995 United Nations' NGO Conference on Women. The series are arranged by organizational or institutional affiliation, and each contains photos, correspondence, press clippings, and literature. Linda May also has a book collection with Special Collections. For separated books, see Separated Materials note.
Biographical Information
Linda May, a writer and feminist political activist, was most active between 1970 and 2000. She attended the 1985 and 1995 United Nations NGO Conferences on Women in Nairobi and Beijing. She also served as a coordinator and speaker at the 1977 National Women's Conference in Houston, Texas. Linda represented the American Jewish Coalition at numerous national and global women's conferences, and was involved with many anti-domestic violence organizations in the Houston area throughout her career.
Separated Materials
Linda May book collection (https://library.uh.edu/search~S11?/aLinda+May+Papers./alinda+may+papers/-3%2C-1%2C0%2CE/2exact&FF=alinda+may+papers&1%2C45%2C)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired on April 9, 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research.
Related Materials
Greater Houston Women's Foundation Records https://findingaids.lib.uh.edu/repositories/2/resources/150
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the papers of Linda May, a Houston feminist activist who coordinated numerous national and global women's conferences and represented the American Jewish Coalition at the 1985 and 1995 United Nations' NGO Conference on Women. The series are arranged by organizational or institutional affiliation, and each contains photos, correspondence, press clippings, and literature. Linda May also has a book collection with Special Collections. For separated books, see Separated Materials note.
Feminism; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Newsletters; Photographs; Posters; Programs (documents); Speeches (documents)
- United Nations NGO Conferences on Women, 1985-1995
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains materials related to Linda May's role as a delegate to the United Nations' NGO Conference on Women in 1985 and 1995.
  - Nairobi, 1985
    - Programs and Correspondence from Nairobi, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Literature and Photos from Nairobi, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Beijing, 1995
    - Photos from Beijing, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Schedules and Programs from Beijing, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Reports from Beijing, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Fact Sheets and Brochures re: Beijing, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Beijing Press and Publicity, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Beijing Speeches, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - American Jewish Coalition Beijing Handbook, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
- Assorted National Women's Conferences, 1969-1990
  This series contains materials related to the National Women's Conference of 1977, the national Panel of American Women, the National Commission on Women, and the White House Conference on Families and Women.
  - National Women's Conference, Houston, 1977
    - Programs, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence and Newsletters, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - National Panel of American Women, 1977
    - Articles and Clippings, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Programs, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Speeches, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Local Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Rosters, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Panelists, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Student Panelists, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1979 Conference (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Jewish-American Panelists, 1982-1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Photos, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Cassette Tape, "Panel of American Women: Panel of American Students", undated (Box 5, Item 2)
      Existence and Location of Copies
      A digital surrogate of this audio cassette tape is available to view on the Special Collections Reading Room computer.
  - National Commission on Women, 1978
    - National Commission on Women, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - White House Conference on Families and Women, 1977
    - Miscellaneous, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Programs, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Western Regional Conference, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Women's Organizations, General, 1977-2000
  This series contains materials related to Houston women's organizations such as the Houston Area Women's Center, the Women's Resource Center of Houston, and the Greater Houston Women's Foundation.
  - General Feminist Pamphlets, 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Houston Area Women's Center, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Women's Resource Center of Houston Newsletters, 1990-2000 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Greater Houston Women's Foundation, 1997-2004 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Cassette tape, "Exclusive Special Edition: 'Greater Houston Women's Foun.'", March 12 1995 (Box 5, Item 3)
- Miscellaneous, 1976-2006
  This series contains miscellaneous materials from Linda May's career, such as news clippings, posters, and assorted ephemera.
  - General Media, 1980
    - Houston Today, Houston Tomorrow, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
    - Cassette tape, "10:45 Lecture, Betty Freidan", August 12 1983 (Box 5, Item 4)
  - News Clippings, 1971-1995
    - Miscellanea, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Map of the NGO Forum on Women - Beijing, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Street Map of Hong Kong, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - "Conference on Families in California: American Jewish Committee's Linda May served as delegate to Western Regional White House meeting", August 1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - "Recipes without prejudice", The Houston Post, May 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - "Trying to reopen the doors slammed shut by prejudice", The News-Sun, April 1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "Prejudice Still Rampant, Women's Panel Tells Church Group", The Houston Chronicle, March 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "Prejudice: Students address issues that many people ignore", The Houston Chronicle, January 1978 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "Barbara Marshall recalls childhood pain but looks hopefully to future", Houston Post, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "What people are doing", The Houston Post, August 1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - "A panel against prejudice: They are trying to change the stereotype people have of minorities and to show that all people are individuals", Houston Post, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Bouquet To The Ladies", The Houston Chronicle, October 1972 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - "The Work is Just Beginning: Beyond Beijing, First of three parts", The Houston Chronicle, October 1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - "Grow Up: Texas holds a lesson for politicians in Washington", The Houston Chronicle, December 1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - "Watchdog Greanias mum on his future", The Houston Chronicle, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - "Sarah Weddington: White House taken for women's affairs?", The Washington Post Magazine, February 1979 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - "Betty Freidan, Who Ignited a Movement in 'The Feminine Mystique,' Dies at 85", The New York Times, February 2006 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - "Nixon Is Quitting: Reputation for Honestly Ford's Appeal", The Houston Chronicle, August 1974 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - "Hookers and Housewives Come Together", Coyote Howls: The Intermittent Journal of A Loose Women's Organization, September 1977 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Daily Breakthrough: Where Women Are News, November 18-20 1977 (Box 3, Folder 19-21)
    - "EGYPT AND ISRAEL SIGN FORMAL TREATY, ENDING A STATE OF WAR AFTER 30 YEARS; SADAT AND BEGIN PRAISE CARTER'S ROLE", The New York Times, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - "Ways to steer clear of a collision with China", The Houston Chronicle, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - "First lady wants help for women", The Houston Post, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - "Some Safety Tips for a Dangerous World", The Wall Street Journal, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - "Women at Risk: Claiming Their Rights", Amnesty International USA, Spring 1995 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Review of Anne Wolfe's "To Be Female and Jewish: Double Jeopardy?," Dead Pans, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - "LINDA MAY RETURNS FROM NAIROBI: Part Two", The Jewish Herald-Voice, August 1985 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Houston Woman, November 1985 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - "4 different views of the Nairobi conference", Houston Chronicle, August 1985 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "LINDA MAY RETURNS FROM NAIROBI: Part I", The Jewish Herald-Voice, August 1985 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - "Did Forum '85 do what the U.N. couldn't in Nairobi?", The Houston Post, August 1985 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - "Jewish women laud Maureen Reagan for success against anti-Zionism at the Nairobi women's conference: President's daughter raps Western European delegates for not publicly supporting U.S. position", The Jewish-Herald Voice, August 1985 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - "There are 200 Jews in Nairobi: And, like most of the other Jews in Kenya, they feel secure and content", Baltimore Jewish Times, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Forum 85, July 19 1985 (Box 3, Folder 35-40)
  - UN Posters, 1980-1995
    - "Action for Equality, Development, and Peace" Beijing '95 Poster, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - "UN 1995" Beijing Poster (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - "Chinese Women Procurators Association" Poster, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - "Women of the World: Celebrating a Decade of Achievement, 1976—1985" Poster (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - "UN Decade for Women: Forum '85" Poster, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - "American Women on the Move: First national Women's Conference" Poster, November 1977 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - "Houston: Back and Forth in the Promised Land" Poster, March 1980 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - "ENSEMBLE" Poster, 1995 (Drawer Z.5, Ovs folder 3)
  - Ephemera, 1993-1995
    - "ET Team" Eleanor Tinsley Campaign Sweatshirt, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - "Turtle Team" Clipboard, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Commemorative handmade placard, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Small glass perfume bottle with painting of four women, 1995 (Box 3, Item 1)
  - T-Shirts, 1994-1995
    - Fourth World Conference on Women, Beijing, 1995 (Box 3, Item 51)
    - Governor Ann Richards, 1994 (Box 3, Item 52)
    - Make Herstory (Hillary), undated (Box 3, Item 53)